{"test_questions": [[{"question": "An excessively high temperature in the fermentation of sauerkraut may inhibit the growth of", "opta": "Leuconostoc", "optb": "Pediococcus cerevisiae", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which statement is true about flavouring materials spices, garlic etc. added to Dill pickles?", "opta": "These markedly stimulate or inhibit the acid forming bacteria", "optb": "They may be source of considerable numbers of undesirable micro-organisms and cause off-fermentations or spoilage of pickles", "optc": "They may improve texture of the pickle", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Shriveling in fermented pickles results from the physical effect of", "opta": "too strong salt solution", "optb": "too strong sugar solution", "optc": "too strong vinegar solution", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Gassy spoilage of green olives is usually caused by", "opta": "Enterobacter  spp", "optb": "Bacillus  spp", "optc": "Clostridium  spp", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Abnormal fermentation of cabbage may result in a cheese like odour caused by", "opta": "propionic acid", "optb": "butyric acid", "optc": "caprioc acid and Valeric acid", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Too long a fermentation of sauerkraut may favour the growth of", "opta": "Lactobacillus lactis", "optb": "Lactobacillus brevis", "optc": "Bacillus subtilis", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Blackening in pickles occurs due to", "opta": "the formation of hydrogen sulfide by bacteria", "optb": "growth of Pencillium", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Soft pickles are made so by pectolytic enzymes mostly from", "opta": "moulds", "optb": "yeasts", "optc": "bacteria", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Hollow pickles are obtained as a result of", "opta": "loose packing in the vat", "optb": "too strong or too weak brine", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The favouring conditions for floaters is", "opta": "high intial amounts of salt", "optb": "thick skin that does not allow gas to diffuse out", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The growth of black-pigmented Bacillus nigrificans, a causative agent of black pickle is favoured by", "opta": "presence of carbohydrate like glucose", "optb": "low level of available nitrogen", "optc": "neutral or slightly alkaline brine", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Black kraut is caused by", "opta": "the plant enzymes", "optb": "the micro-organisms", "optc": "the combined actions of plant enzymes and micro-organisms", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Floaters or bloaters may result from", "opta": "hollow cucumbers", "optb": "gas being formed by yeasts", "optc": "hetero fermentative lactic acid bacteria", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Slippery pickles occur due to", "opta": "growth of encapsulated bacteria", "optb": "broken scums of film yeasts on the surface of brine", "optc": "addition of high amount of salt", "optd": "both (a) and (b)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Slimy or ropy kraut is caused by", "opta": "encapsulated varieties of Lactobacillus plantarum", "optb": "Lactobacillus lactis", "optc": "encapsulated varieties of Lactobacillus brevis", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The most important bacterium developing acidity in both low and high salt brines is", "opta": "L. lactis", "optb": "L. plantarum", "optc": "L. brevis", "optd": "B. subtilis", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The elimination of the scum of yeasts in the brine during the fermentation include", "opta": "agitation of the surface", "optb": "addition of the mustard oil", "optc": "addition of the sorbic acid", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cloudiness of brine of glass-packed olives may be caused by", "opta": "the lactics if fermentation of residual sugar resumes", "optb": "salt-tolerant bacteria", "optc": "film yeasts or moulds if air is available", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}